Ankur Singh

■ ankur13019@iiitd.ac.in (+91)9717193630 New Delhi, India f rush.skills ankurs13 in /in/ankursingh13 rush-skills

SUMMARY

I am a CSE junior at IIIT Delhi, a developer and a hacker. A Full Stack Developer, I build websites in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript, write scripts in Python, familiar with Android apps in Java. I am experienced in building a product: ideation, prototyping, developing, deploying, and scaling. Additionally, I have closely worked with a Bitcoin research group at my institute. I actively work as a freelance developer, having several successful projects in the past. I have been an active part of my Institute community (Both technically and non-technically). My management and organizational skills have been honed by my work in and outside my Institute.

EMPLOYMENT

IIIT-Delhi

Teaching Assistant | Confab Mentor · 2014 to 2015

- Volunteer TA for Intro To Programming '14 & '15: Taught concepts of basic programming in Python and C, conducted weekly tutorials for a group of 30 students.
- TA for C Refresher Module '15: Taught concepts of basic C to incoming batch of freshers.
- Confab Mentor for Data Structures and Algorithms '15: Tutored freshers taking the course weekly about fundamental concepts of data structures.
- TA for IIITD IT Department '15: Aided in setting up and maintaining servers and IT infrastructure.

Backpack Labs

Developer · May 2014 to Dec 2014

My work as a part of the web team, involved building the new version of the product with a completely new interface adding features like grading, improving the speed of the product, and building the attendance module.

AWARDS

PolicyHack · Grand Prize Winner

Won the PolicyHack hackathon organized by EPoD Harvard as a part of a 4-member team. Designed and developed an IoT solution to track leaking and hijacked water tankers in the city. The prize was a week long trip to Harvard Kennedy School, where I got to interact with the EPoD team.

HackDelhi · 1st Prize Jul 2015

Winner of the HackDelhi hackathon as a part of 2-member team. Build a product to detect fake products on eCommerce websites.

HackCancer @ EPIC, Boston University · Oct **2nd Prize Winner** 2015

2nd prize winner of HackCancer hackathon in EPIC, Boston University as part of a 3-member team. Built an extension that monitors the websites(Visited by the cancer patients) and alerts their families if they are viewing potentially dangerous content: self-medication and outdated treatments.

AngelHack Delhi · Jun

2nd Prize, IBM Category | 5th Prize, Overall 2015

Prize winner - AngelHack Delhi hackathon, for Retromoves project as a part of 5-member team.

EDUCATION

IIIT Delhi

B. Tech. CSE 2017

PROJECTS

Sync Youtube On High

Made an android app to play the same YouTube video across multiple devices in sync. Got featured as Devpost Staff Pick for the week.

Retromoves

Made a mobile app - alongside 4 people - that allows you to play games on your computer by leveraging all the great motion sensors in your smartphones. It gives a kinect-like experience, as you move your phone around, it moves the player on the screen.

Esya 2015 Website

Built a website for Esya'15, our annual techfest, which has the looks and feel of an online IDE and has an emulated terminal to play with. Got over 1 lakh hits and was a huge success.

Building PaaS for our Data Center

We are building Heroku-like PaaS for our data center shifting from VMs to docker clusters.

100people | Incredible India

We analysed the census and other open data of India and each state and represent it in a extremely simple way - by scaling down the population and asking the question - What if India had a population of 100 people? Then the data is represented in form of downloadable minimal posters.

ACTIVITIES

Byld (Software Dev club) · Admin

Aug 2015 to Current

hackIIITD · Organizer

Aug 2015

Apr 2015

Innovate Delhi (IDEA) · Student Entrepreneur

Jun 2014

Europe-India Conclave · Volunteer Organizer

Dec 2015

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python, Ruby, Javascript, Java, HTML5, C, SOI

Development: Ruby on Rails, Flask, Sinatra, Redis, MySQL,

PostgreSQL, HTML5, CSS3, Angular, Bootstrap, AJAX, MongoDB,

Android, Phonegap, jQuery, Scrapy

Tools and Technologies: Linux, Docker, Sublime Text, Android Studio, AWS Git

General Skills: Event Management, Public Speaking, Communication, Leadership, Networking, Analytics

VOLUNTEERING

Helping Hands Initiative · Volunteer/Teacher

An initiative of IIIT Delhi to help students of small government schools to learn and become better.